If you open your terminal and type python,
如果你打开终端并输入 python
you should see something like this.
应该会看到这样的结果
This is the python interactive interpreter.
这是 python 交互式解释器
You can type here to interact with Python directly.
你可以在这里输入命令 直接与 Python 交互
You just type your code,
只需输入代码
press enter and the output will appear on the following line.
按下 Enter 键 输出将出现在下一行
This is a good place to experiment and try bits of Python code at a time.
可以在此处每次尝试一些 Python 代码
Notice here, I didn't have to print the type to see the output.
注意我不需要输出类型就能看到结果
In the interpreter, the value of the last line
在解释器中 提示符中的最后一行的值
in a prompt will be outputted automatically.
将自动输出
If you had multiple lines where you'd want output values,
如果有多行需要输出值
you'd still have to print.
依然需要手动输出
If you start to define a function,
如果你开始定义函数
you will see a change in the prompt to signify that this is a continuation line.
你会发现提示符窗口发生了变化 表示这是一个连续的行
You'll have to include your own indentation as you defined the function.
在定义函数时 你需要自己进行缩进
A drawback of the interpreter is that it's tricky to edit code.
解释器的不足之处是修改代码比较麻烦
If you made a mistake when typing
如果你在定义该函数时出错了
this function or forgot to indent the body of the function,
或者忘记缩进函数的主体部分
you can't use a mouse to click your cursor where you want it.
你无法用鼠标点击光标
You have to navigate with the arrow keys to move
需要使用箭头键来回移动
the cursor forwards and backwards to the line itself for editing.
转到要修改的行
It would be helpful for you to learn useful shortcuts
有必要了解一些实用的快捷键
for actions like moving to the beginning or end of the line.
以便快速转到一行的开头或结尾
Notice, I can reference any objects I defined earlier in the interpreter.
注意 我可以引用之前在解释器中定义的任何对象
One useful trick is using the up and down arrow
一个实用技巧是使用上下箭头键
to cycle through your recent commands at the interactive prompt.
在交互式提示符窗口中循环浏览最近的命令
This can be useful to rerun or adapt code you've already tried.
这样可以重新运行或调整已经尝试的代码
To quit the python interactive interpreter,
要退出 python 交互式解释器
use the command exit with parentheses or hit control
输入命令 exit()
D on mac or linux or control Z and enter for Windows.
或者在 Mac 或 Linux 上按下 Ctrl+D 在 Windows 上按下 Ctrl+Z
There's actually a really good alternative to the default python interpreter.
实际上有一个比默认 python 解释器更好用的替代工具
IPython which comes as many additional features like
即 IPython 它具有很多其他功能
tab completion which completes words for you
例如 Tab 补齐功能 它可以为你补充完整的单词
or shows what options are available if there are multiple.
或者如果有多个选项 显示有哪些选项
This can be useful if you want to see what methods are available for an object.
这样可以查看某个对象有哪些可用的方法
Another useful check is this question mark to get details about a particular object.
另一个实用功能是问号 可以用来获取关于特定对象的详细信息
I can quickly see what this function does without looking up the documentation.
我可以快速查看这个函数的作用 不用打开文档
You can also execute system shell commands using
还可以使用感叹号执行系统 shell 命令
an exclamation point and some common ones don't even require it.
一些常见命令甚至不需要感叹号
You can learn more about IPython in the notes below.
你可以在下面的注释中详细了解 IPython
Using an interpreter can be really helpful for experimenting and testing python code.
解释器非常有用 可以用来实验和测试 python 代码
Those not necessarily just for experimentation.
并且不止实验作用
I also used an interpreter when I want to quickly
在使用 Python 时 我还会使用解释器
investigate or modify files using Python.
快速调查或修改文件